BEN SBANOTTO

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

479-409-6910

<u>ben.sbanotto@gmail.com</u>

Tulsa, OK

in https://linkedin.com/in/ben-sbanotto

https://github.com/bsbanotto

SKILLS

Python

Bash

MySQL

SQLAlchemy

Tensorflow

Numpy

Jupyter Notebook

• CV2

- Six Sigma
- Pandas
- Matplotlib
- Minitab

JavaScript

HTMLCSS

Project Management

Design Thinking

EDUCATION

DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND MACHINE LEARNING

Holberton Tulsa

Anticipated Graduation - Dec 2023

20 month software engineering school where students learn through peer and project-based learning

B.S. MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

Arkansas Tech University

2006 - 2010

A.S. NUCLEAR TECHNOLOGY

Arkansas Tech University

2006 - 2010

PROFILE

Professional with 10+ years of using data to identify problems across various manufacturing industries to implement sustainable solutions. Excited to combine professional and technical team leadership experience with a robust technical skill set to add immediate value and ensure company success.

PROJECTS

OBJECT DETECTION - YOLO V3

Apr 2023

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/bsbanotto/object_detection

Solo Project

- Created a custom implementation of YOLO V3 algorithm trained on the COCO dataset to detect objects in selected photographs
- Built bounding boxes to display confidences around identified objects

Technologies: Python, Tensorflow Keras, CV2

SPACE-BUBBLES

Dec 2022

Group Project

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/bsbanotto/space-bubbles

- Developed an emulator of Space Invaders mashed with Bubble Shooter during a four day sprint by working on a team with 2 peers
- Included a local leaderboard for high score tracking in a SQLite database

Technologies: Python, Pygame, SQLite

EXPERIENCE

STUDENT TUTOR

Holberton Tulsa

Aug 2022 - Present

- Conducted bi-monthly live coding sessions for up to 80 students on upcoming concepts, offering guidance based on lessons and experiences gained through the initial learning of these concepts
- Provided 10 to 15 hours of weekly ad-hoc tutoring sessions for students covering Bash scripting, the C language, Python, and SQL

ENGINEERING MANAGER

Carlisle Brake and Friction

Jun 2011 - Dec 2018

- Led a team of 10 Process Engineers in a manufacturing plant throughout a 2-year plant closure project, ensuring a 95%+ on-time delivery to customers while achieving annual savings of \$750,000
- Served as a Site Subject Matter Expert and contributed to a global team responsible for the launch of a cloud-based software for global product lifecycle management